Translation: The Sixteen Little Statics Are Discovered by Dimorus Machsel Zhang
Proofreading: Machsel Zhang XVI Rosa
Shaft\Pressure: HollaBella Yellow Peach Messenger Machsel Zhang
Welcome to follow Sina Weibo @马赫塞勒张 to get the video download address with embedded Chinese and English subtitles and translator annotations
The translations used in this subtitle when referring to the original text of the "Bible" are based on the "Mandarin Chinese Union Version" ("God" version)
The Psychological Significance of the Story of the Bible Lecture 5 Cain and Abel——The Destruction of Ideals by Jordan B. Peterson
I want to read something for you
I received a lot of letters
I forgot where this letter came from
I have been to many different places last week
And this letter comes from one of the places
I'll read it to you
I don't know what to think about this myself
This should be written by a lady
I can only guess this
No address and name on it
"This is not a question but a statement
"Or more accurately maybe it's a revelation."
"I attended an Ayahuasca ceremony last weekend
"If you haven't heard of it,
"This is a South American hallucinogenic herb"
"Maybe some of you will disdain this
"But Ayahuasca can bring you directly
"The Prototype World of Being"
"Those who try this drug should say that the first try
"I will call Ayahuasui "she"
"Because the spirit of this plant is absolutely feminine
"And the encounter with Ayahuasca is
"With the Mother Earth Goddess of Creation
"The Void Encounter of the Source of Everything
"It's the feminine equivalent of Logos."
"Dr. Peterson
"You appeared in my Ayahuasca illusion"
This may be the reason why I am so tired recently
"Dr. Peterson
"You appeared in my Ayahuasca illusion
"Then I asked her who Jordan Peterson is"
"What is he doing?"
I want to know this too
"She answered clearly
"『He is here to wake up and teach
""The Holy Way of Masculine on Earth""
"So I am here to represent
"The great mother is the goddess
"And the holy feminine way, thank you sincerely
"She has been eagerly looking forward to
"The awakening of the masculine way merges into the divinity and serves it"
You can’t get this kind of letter every day
Actually, I receive one or two such letters every day
When I read it, what I thought in my head was
Of course this is a completely crazy analogy
But as a psychotherapist
One thing I learned is
Tell the client what I think at this time
I'm not thinking exactly
That's not the same thing
What comes to my mind is more like a dream
It is spontaneous as imagined
If you are thinking
Then there will be an active ingredient, right
I mean, God knows how we think
But at least part of it is actively involved
Jung thought it was
Dialogue between conscious and unconscious mind
It is a continuous conversation
But when things suddenly come to your mind
It's like walking into a room suddenly
There is something in the room
By the way
This is also an inspiration I got from Jung
He pointed out very correctly
People are not really thinking
But those thoughts are showing to them
So you can extract these ideas
And criticize them, etc.
Instead of just assuming they are correct
But people don’t usually do
As long as an idea suddenly appears in their minds
They will believe it
Anyway, one thing I often do in psychotherapy is
Tell people what's in my head
why
Because the person who talks to me like this
Can receive an undisturbed view
This is not even an opinion but a reaction
I think this is really not an opinion
The point of view may be the result of my thinking
It has a subjective meaning
I suddenly thought of a story about Socrates
He was
At the trial for poisoning the youth of the whole country
By the way, I have also been charged with the same crime
But what I think is obvious is
It’s not me who is doing the so-called poisoning
So someone once asked the priestess of the Temple of Delphi
The Temple of Delphi is equivalent to a place of retreat
If you are an ancient Greek citizen
You will have a dream when you go there
Then you will go to the priestess of Delphi to interpret the dream
No one really understands the priestess of Delphi today
And her psionic principles
Anyway, she can explain your dream
Someone once asked her who is the wisest person in Greece
Delphi priestess said it was Socrates
Because he knows he doesn't understand anything
This story is probably like this
This story appeared in my mind at the time
It's crazy to compare myself to Socrates
But my mind is already wild
So I can accept this result
Now i have to do something
I haven't done this before
I want to read you a little
I mentioned before that I finished my book last week
I haven't read it to anyone
I only shared with a few friends and asked them to proofread
Here is a special mention of someone
A screenwriter named Greg Herwitz
His help to me is immense
He is efficient and accurate in this type of work
If I send him a 20-page manuscript
He will edit the article drastically
And send it back to me within 90 minutes
It's incredible
He is really good at this job
Helped me a lot
But no one has read these manuscripts except my editor
I haven't read it to anyone
But some of them seem to be particularly suitable for tonight’s lecture
So I think tonight’s lecture will start with these articles
Taken from the chapter on sacrifice
This is about Abraham and Isaac
It’s a very strange Old Testament story
This kind of story contained in the Old Testament
May make us modern people feel
Maybe we should
Keep your distance from the Old Testament
Especially to the God in the Old Testament
Stay away
For Abraham
God originally wanted him to sacrifice his son
It turns out that God just made a joke with him
I'm obviously shivering when I say this
But this does raise a question
What do you think of a god who would make such a request
Or vice versa
What do you think of Abraham, a man with similar hallucinations
In any case, the credibility of this story in the eyes of modern people
And the moral integrity of the Old Testament.
These are some very bizarre stories
They often deviate from the appearance or are consistent
They have far-reaching connotations than appearances
Tonight we will talk a lot about sacrifice
I always have my own ideas about sacrifice
These thoughts are written in my book
In "The Antidote to the Chaos of the Twelve Rules of Life"
This book will be published in January I think I mentioned
I am going to read the seventh rule
"Go for something meaningful
The paragraph in "not short-term benefits"
This is what I have in the past three years
Some articles on the subject of sacrifice
Before reading this article, let me briefly introduce
It took me a long time to understand
The meaning of sacrifice in the Old Testament is strange
But when I understand
The meaning seems to become obvious
It's the kind of feeling that suddenly realized
Because many times if you understand something correctly
As long as you understand it correctly it will be obvious
Then let's try it together
This method seems to work for me anyway
I used to just vaguely understand
Modern usage of the concept of sacrifice
Everyone actually understands the subject
If you want to make things better in the future
Then you have to make sacrifices now
Even your family needs to do this for generations
Especially when you are a good parent
I think immigration is a typical example, right
Immigrants often come from bad places
If they want to join a new community that is hostile to them
Often have to pay a huge price
They will have a hard life
They do this mainly to make their lives
And their children’s lives become better
Fortunately when they arrived in Canada
Compared to their hometown
Life really got better
The place where they came is worse but here is relatively better
Even so
Immigrants still need to work hard
To regain a foothold
They must learn a new language
Embrace the influence of new culture
And face the fact that they are not part of the mainstream culture
Anyway, you should all have heard of such stories
So you make sacrifices for the future
The idea of ​​making sacrifices for your children
Everyone can understand this
This is a sign of responsible maturity
It’s the performance of correctly shouldering the burden of life
If you discipline yourself, you will do it
In fact, this is almost the definition of self-discipline
Self-discipline means you have the ability to make sacrifices
If you just do what you want to do more
You don’t have self-discipline instead of what you focus on
That's not self-discipline
If it works then that works
If you mix well in that way, that's fine
But this is still not self-discipline
Self-discipline is when you want to do something right away
You will think "No, I have to delay my desire first"
Maybe a permanent delay
Or at least in the medium to long term
You focus on what you think
Things that will produce results in the medium to long term
You look ahead and decide
Less satisfy today's impulse
You will make your future more reliable
More fruitful
And you really did it
But it is not easy
Last week we discussed
Adam and Eve's discovery of the future
And reveal the possibilities of the future
This includes the possibility of future tragedy and suffering
Is what we might
Recognition of the tragedy and suffering
Prompt us to make the sacrifice of the moment
So that we can reduce unnecessary anxiety
Uncertainty and pain
Admittedly this is a negative view
But we can also do this for some happiness
To make life better and so on
This is not a trivial matter
But the most fundamental problem is
Especially when you have a baby
The most fundamental problem is to avoid pain, right
Everyone thinks so
This is your first moral obligation
If you can at least recognize reality
This is your most important duty
So you will make the necessary sacrifices
To create the future
The theme of sacrifice is found in the Old Testament
But it's so real
So that it is difficult to compare between the two
It is not obvious to me that they are consistent
I don’t remember when I went to United Church when I was a child
During the very limited religious education
I always went to the United Church until I was 13
I don't remember anyone explained to me
The sacrifice of Cain and Abel
Or Abraham's attempted sacrifice
Or is it the sacrifice of people to God
Is a dramatic sign, it heralds sacrifice
Will become a psychological concept recognized by modern civilization
This is obvious as I said before
Once you put things in perspective, it will suddenly become clear
No one explained these things to me
I'd better read the book
I just finished introducing this matter
"With the development of mankind, these things happened
"First of all, before written history and drama
"That tens of thousands or hundreds of thousands of years
"Delay and exchange behaviors began to emerge
"And this process is slow and painful."
There is a cool psychology study
This is called the "marshmallow test"
Is it a reliable study?
Although it was done by social psychologists
This experiment should be reproducible
Is a good study
You choose some kids
Take to a room
Then put what they want in front of them
Like a marshmallow
Then you basically start to "torture" them
You said, "Did you see that cotton candy?"
The child will think "Yes, I saw cotton candy"
You say, "You can eat marshmallows now
"Or if you wait a minute"
I remember the experiment stipulated ten minutes
"You can eat two marshmallows."
This presents a problem for the children
They are required to use
An actual concrete tangible marshmallow
To exchange two imaginary future marshmallows
Imagine the reality of a hypothetical future
And the reality in front of you
Has the same tangible meaning
Not an easy task
It's amazing that people can do this
Then the experimenter left
Some kids grab the marshmallow and eat it
There are some children, they recorded the children
The children began to show different reactions after they left
They whistled and looked at the ceiling
Sitting on one's hands
They try to distract themselves
Of course they will stare at the marshmallows from time to time
Like a squirrel staring at a nut
They will try to restrain themselves
This reminds me of the child’s prefrontal cortex
This higher cortical system
Is at war with the underlying motivation system
Those who control things like hunger
More primitive motivation system
Hunger system hypothalamic system
Would say, "There are some high-fat and high-sugar things right in front of me
"Act now
"Grab that thing and put it in your mouth."
I believe many of you often
Because whether to eat something high in fat and sugar
And fight with the hypothalamus
And often lose
So you may be able to see the situation of those children firsthand
The hypothalamus has very powerful tendrils
Implant the brain deeply
Enter the part that is mainly responsible for our autonomous control
The autonomous control center has some small weak ribbons
Downward control of the hypothalamus
If you know something about neuroanatomy
Can easily understand that at the critical moment
Which part is controlling
For children to learn to control
Those underlying primitive impulses are not easy
These impulses are born
We share with animals
But the kids will control and it’s cool
This was discovered by Walter Michel
Is the research he did
He found that for those in the marshmallow test
For children who can postpone satisfaction
Their long-term human generation is better than those
Children who ate marshmallows impulsively and immediately had much more positive results
This is "delayed gratification"
This is probably related to responsibility
Although this specific connection has not yet been determined
But they look very similar in concept
Anyway, this situation may occur in
It’s almost like this for two to four year olds
They should be prepared before the age of four
Because for them
Learn not to delay gratification
It’s difficult to interact well with other children
If you can't delay gratification
No other kids will like you
Because you will be arbitrary
You need to be satisfied immediately
And you lose your temper easily
In short you don't have
Self-control to get along with others happily
You can see this in children, it's funny
Not only that when the behavior of satisfying the delay first appears
It heralds positive long-term results
By the way, the responsibility trait has the same effect
In western culture
Responsibility is the second major factor for long-term success
It is second only to intelligence
In our society
Those who have done the best in all periods
Those who work hard with high IQ
I want to say I think this phenomenon is pretty good
how to say
It's an illustration
It can prove that our culture is positive
I think you need
If this system is truly elite-led
And it should be so
And you want to learn from people who are more effective in contributing
If you get resources there
Then what you want to happen is
Let those who work hard and smart have a better life
Everyone can live better because of this
I hope so
anyway
You can see the ability to delay gratification
Is developed in the children
"At first before written history and drama appeared
"Humanity has more than 100,000 years of history."
"Delay and exchange the twin behaviors
"Begin to appear slowly and painfully"
"Then they are expressed in a metaphysical abstract form
"Such as rituals and sacrificial legends"
"Like there is a powerful character in the sky judging you
"You better please him or be cautious in your words and deeds."
"We have been observing ourselves for a long time with God."
"When you give up what you treasure
"He seems to be happy"
"So practice sharing and sacrifice
"Until you know it."
"No one really said this."
It’s been a long time, even if someone said something similar
"But these views are implicit in the action
"Hidden in the story"
"Action first, implicit first"
"People observe these successes and failures
"It's been thousands of years."
"We think twice and come to a conclusion
"Successful among us will make sacrifices
"Successful among us will delay enjoyment
"Successful among us will play against the future"
"A great idea"
"Gradually formed in an unprecedented form."
"The idea is the key to a long and profound story."
"It is the moral of this story."
I want to make a foreshadowing here
"What is the difference between successful and unsuccessful"
"Successful people will make sacrifices
"After they make sacrifices, things will get better."
"The problem has become more precise but also broader."
"What is for the greatest good
"The greatest sacrifice ever made."
If you ask for this purpose
Maybe there will be a moment
You can’t make it more precise and broad
At this moment this question is in a sense
Or maybe even the answer to that question
Became a prototype
Become a prototype because it can no longer be optimized
In a sense it seems to be the ultimate problem
How could it be possible to ask a broader question?
Assumed initial preset
You have to make sacrifices
Then the logical end point will look like this
Good you have to make sacrifices
That for the greatest good
And what is the greatest sacrifice made
This is a good question
"The answer will become profound."
"God in the traditional sense of the West
"Similar to other gods that require sacrifice."
"We have explored the reason."
"But sometimes God’s requirements are even higher
"High enough to require you to sacrifice your favorite."
"That's why"
"It's also another major human discovery."
"Sometimes things don't go well"
"It's obvious and ordinary."
"But there is a contradiction."
"Sometimes when things get blocked
"The obstacle to this matter happens to be the most cherished thing."
"Why because the world is
"Shown with your values ​​as a template"
"If the world you see is not what you want
"At this time you should reflect on your values."
"It's time to pull yourself out of the current assumptions."
I believe that in this lecture series
I have mentioned a famous experiment many times
The "Invisible Gorilla" experiment
In the "Invisible Gorilla" experiment, there are two teams of players
Three members per team
A team in black and a team in white
Each team passes each other within the team
And it's all around
You can watch videos of their experiments
They almost filled the whole shot
The white team passes the ball to the white team member
The black team passes the ball to the black team member
Your task for this experiment
Is clear
Number of passes of black team members
This is what you want
At this time you have to pursue goals and values
Pursuing goals and values ​​at this time are the same thing
Is to complete this task
This is very cool very cool
This fact is incredible
Like a complete verification of an element in the Buddhist worldview
They pass the ball
The experimenter asked you how many times
You said 15 times that you are happy
Because you are focused
The experimenter said it was good
Maybe it’s not that you may have missed one
Then the experimenter will say
So did you see that gorilla
Half of the people would say
What gorilla is kidding
The experimenter said, "Yes." He rewinds and replays
About half of the three-minute video
There is indeed a man who is 1.9 meters tall
Walked into the camera in a gorilla suit
He stands in the middle of the playing field
Almost as tall as other players
Extremely eye-catching and unobtrusive
He beat his chest for about a second and a half
Then he swaggered down
At that time, half of the people did not see this gorilla
This is really shocking
It illustrates your quest
Will make you invisible to the essence of reality
Your pursuit will give you an insight into some of the reality
And ignore most of the rest of the reality
This is normal
Because you can't
In a sense most of you can’t
You are a very focused creature like a laser beam
So I can’t pay attention to everything all the time
But once you realize a problem you will ask yourself
If you feel miserable then there is a possibility
That is, you may be too focused on one point
So that your focus may be entirely around
"Why are things so bad?" The question comes up
But it may not be
Because life is so random
You will suffer even when you don’t deserve it
This looks like a story from "Job"
Job is a good man but God made a bet with Satan
This seems to be another vicious act
Torture Job
Satan did a great job
I want to see if Job will disobey God
This seems to be very interesting to God
But the point is that even in the Old Testament
There are also ample signs
Sometimes people are devastated and bruised
Even if they have good conduct and high ambitions
Life is still a bit random
What may hurt you is what you are attached to
It may even be the thing you are most attached to
Will hurt you the most
This is most likely the person you love
Many times when I give people a psychological diagnosis and treatment
They suffer for some reason
Sometimes just because of a bad relationship with close family members
In short, their family members
I don’t really want to lead them to a good life
Instead, these family members
But want to bring them in
In the most tragic situation possible
And maliciously use kinship to fulfill their wishes
So sometimes necessary sacrifice
Not only to keep a physical distance from that person
And sometimes seriously alienating those people
Such as old and dead
It's really hard and painful
But this is also a very good example
It shows that sometimes in order to never fall into
Withdraw from pain and chaos
You must give up your beloved
"If the world you see is not what you want
"Then you need to reflect on your own values."
I need to think about it
Because its other option is to curse fate
If it's not your problem, you can't change
Because you didn't do anything wrong
Then the problem lies with Destiny World and others
The reason is that these are all parts of the world
In other words, the problem lies in the nature of the world itself
Or the problem lies in "God" itself
This god can be any god you believe or not
Because no matter what kind of faith you have
Will encounter the situation I described
There is a very interesting thing
I mentioned before about the Israelites in the Old Testament
They understand this is not trivial
In the Old Testament the Israelites over and over again
The magic of being complacent
Immediately afterwards committed a moral error
Because they are proud and complacent
Then God split them to pieces
Cycle after generation
They got up tremblingly
But has always maintained the same attitude
"We made a mistake, we made a mistake."
This leads to an axiom instead of observation
That is, "If things are not shown as they are
"Then we should not curse God
"I should reflect on myself"
You will ask why not curse God
Because it might also be his fault
This is a good question
I have been thinking about this problem for 30 years
Why not curse god
Because existence is arbitrary
Moreover, we are fragile and unbearable
This is all the problem right
There are unjust, unfair and endless suffering in the world
Why not blame God for all this
Regardless of whether God exists
This has nothing to do with the metaphysical elements on this issue
The conclusion remains the same regardless of whether God exists
I can say the answer is still
"If you don’t want to take responsibility
"Trying to give responsibility to society or beings themselves
"That is to make things worse and worse."
"Not only to you but to everyone
"It may even be to the being itself."
It's useless
If you think it's your problem
The problem is with you
Maybe this is not true at all
Maybe you are the one tortured by God and Satan
If this is the case, you are unlucky
But this is still applicable to a human being
People need to stand on their own feet
Have the courage to take responsibility
No matter how opposed
This is really amazing
"It's time to pull yourself out of the current assumptions."
I see it as a "rotten wood problem"
Think about the subject of Phoenix
I remember when Harry Potter went to war
Like a saint george going to war
What's that thing called
Basilisk, your eyes will be turned into stone as long as you touch him
This is the dragon for all intents and purposes
It's watching the virgin
What's her name? It's not "Virginia"
But is it called "Ginny" that is closer?
A variant of the word "Ginny Fla" and "Virgin"
It is also a variant of the word "Virginia"
When Harry Potter was bitten and poisoned by this dragon
This is the dragon of chaos right
When you look at this dragon, it will petrify
When he was bitten and dying
Also if you are bitten by something
If it turns into stone at a glance
If you're not dead, you're better than dead
This is one of two things
Then the phoenix flew in
It poured tears into the wound and healed him
Phoenix this creature
You can let the deadwood burn out every now and then
I think the phoenix is ​​reborn every 100 years
Of course it's very dramatic
This bird needs to nirvana in flames
Then there is only one egg left
But there is also a very serious message
In a sense you can compare yourself to a forest
The forest burns every now and then to clean up the dead wood
Only in this way can the forest stay long
If you don’t let the forest burn for a long time,
Like it happened in the U.S.
Especially when their forest fire control is too strict
The result is a large accumulation of deadwood
Accumulate less and more
Until the whole forest is covered with deadwood
Then he was struck by lightning
Finally turned into a piece of scorched earth
This is a valuable moral lesson
That is, don’t wait for too much deadwood to pile up before burning
Maybe let the forest burn itself a small amount every day
It’s only burned once more than 20 years.
In the end, there is nothing left
Because maybe this will leave you with nothing
But things often happen to people
Commonplace
The deadwood accumulates and it will be a mess around it
Unresolved chaos will add up
One day a spark will appear
The power of a prairie prairie can be described as devastating
By then it will be too late
They are the ones eaten by dragons
Was swallowed into the dragon's belly
This is another common prototype theme
Or there will be a hero to save them
Or they will stay in their belly
This is the sign of "hell"
I don't recommend doing this
So prevent the slightest failure
Much better than sporadic unexpected changes
"It's time to pull yourself out of the current assumptions."
One more thing
Solzhenitsyn said when he wrote about the Soviet Union and its morbidity
"When its pathological totalitarianism reached its peak
"It is illegal to complain about your bad life."
You think about how scary this is
Because it’s not good enough
And I’m not referring to casual situations
I'm talking about, for example, you have diabetes
Facing a serious situation like amputation
This is not a trivial matter
This is a disaster
For another example, you may be unemployed at the economic level
But you see what the Soviet Union did
"We already have the answer"
"Everything is perfect"
This is a totalitarian idea
"If everything is perfect and you are suffering"
"Then the problem may be with you."
After all everything is perfect and you are suffering
What should you do
Stand up and say you are suffering
Then you are proof that the facts are not perfect
You are like the widower and orphan in the Old Testament story
When the throne is high
I don’t care about widowers and orphans
Then the prophet came out and said
"These widowers orphans are far more important than you think."
"If you don’t give proper attention
"Then things around you will
"Fall apart in a way you didn't expect"
You are like your own widower and orphan
But you can't say
See things are not perfect yet
Because I still suffer here
Then you can't admit that you are suffering
If you don’t admit that you are suffering
Pain especially excessive pain
Should be seen as an evidence
Prove that you did something wrong
This should be regarded as proof that you have made a mistake
There is a problem with something big you are doing
I know it's hard
It’s not that some people are suffering
Suffering because they are doing something wrong with some simple methods
I was in the elevator of the hospital once
It's a terrible experience
Came in alone
Completely panicked
It must be bad
I forgot how to speak
Anyway, I exchanged a few words with him
He said he had just been diagnosed as
Suspected advanced cancer
The scary thing is that he began to look back on his life in the elevator
I want to find out what evil he did to suffer this disaster
He soon blamed this on his own moral corruption
That was not what I meant
You can't say to a person with cancer
If you haven't lived so stupidly in your life
You won't get cancer
Believe me, things like this are more common than you think
The severely ill person is blamed
I didn't mean it
That's not the case
The more general attitude should be
If life is still not satisfactory
Then your first responsibility is to act on it
Reflect on your mistakes and change the past
This is absolutely true
Because maybe you are doing unnecessary things
Things will get better if you solve them
"Let down
"Sacrifice the present to create the future"
"There is an old story about catching monkeys"
Maybe someone here is interested in catching monkeys
Now you have a chance to learn
First you have to find a large narrow-necked jar
The top diameter only needs to be enough for him to put the monkey paw in
Then install half of the stone
This way the monkey can't move
Then get some food around the jar to attract its attention
Then put some more food in the jar
If you are lucky, the monkey will come
It will grab the food
Still want to eat what's in the jar
I will stick my paw in to find
If you trap well done
It just can't pull it out
Because it got food
Now if the monkey doesn’t let go
Don't give up
One just needs to walk over and catch the monkey
Monkeys don’t know how to sacrifice
It's just a monkey
Then you can catch it
Because it can’t control hypothalamic desire
If you want to be kind to monkeys
Put sugar or something outside
Monkeys can only eat sugar a few times
Then it won't do everything like you do
But you know what I mean
"People can go to the jar and catch the monkey."
"Animals will not give up parts for the whole"
Is this a good conclusion?
Animals will not give up parts for the whole
"Maybe this story is a bit false
"But a paranoid psychology professor once told me
"'Fictions are used to deceive people in as real a way as possible.'"
"If you give up valuable things, you can ensure future success."
"Things of value can please God after being sacrificed"
Both have the same meaning
One of them is more clear
I think it's the first
The second one is more dramatic
You might think the latter is more like
Embedded in the dream of collective religion
"What is the most valuable and worthy of sacrifice"
Obviously it depends on culture and time
"At least you can ask what is more iconic"
Such as "the method of meat division"
For example, if you are a herder
Then this is the big event
Generally speaking, looking at human history
Meat is a valuable commodity
In chimpanzees too
Chimpanzees like to hunt colobus monkeys
And basically eat live
The colobus weighs about 18 kg
Will keep screaming when eaten
This is interesting
One thing can be seen in male chimpanzees
Refers to the male chimpanzees who go out hunting
Males are not very restrained when hunting
Or you can say that you are not very sympathetic
Certain human behaviors are indeed reminiscent of this
This kind of thing can often be seen on the human battlefield
A group of people give up all internal regulations
To a certain extent
Make you wonder whether the internal regulations exist
Just to get meat because meat is precious
There is a good literature
Books published not long ago
It's about a book about humans inventing fire
I said a little about this before
Langham thinks we invented fire
Mastered how to use fire approximately 2 to 3 million years ago
This is much earlier than people thought
This has truly transformed us physically
From ancestors similar to chimpanzees
Until now, this slender looks
Cooked meat is better digested
Meat is an important source of nutritional energy required by the human body
Especially cooked meat
So meat is important
Cooked meat is important
The same applies to the choice of meat
The meat you will choose when you greet guests if you are not one
I keep saying the word wrong
Is it called vegan?
Still called Vega (Vega)
I always say Vega but I read it wrong
Vega (Vega) is a star, right?
Vegans are not star creatures
You have to eat meat for the guests anyway
Especially when guests come to visit your house
And you are a herder
Then you have to make some high-end meat
Use the best part of the meat to entertain guests
This is really important
This is very meaningful and good livestock
What's up
Speaking of things you can sacrifice
It can be your best livestock
How about sacrificing yourself and your children
In terms of hierarchy, children should be ranked behind
This is a bit hard to accept right
It’s like throwing a coin, hard to choose
From the perspective of sacrifice, you are more precious
Or your child is more precious
I have to say as a parent
Children are more precious
Most people have established
It’s hard to say "appropriate", but let’s just say so
Established a suitable relationship with the child
Parents will block bullets for their children in critical moments
Let the child survive
"Mother's sacrifice was Michelangelo
"Deeply displayed in the form of the great sculpture "The Pieta""
"The Virgin Mary stares at the crucified son"
Jesus' body was nailed to the cross
"It's her fault"
"Through her, Jesus participated in the drama of beings."
So what is the meaning of this sculpture
This is a great work
Incredible work
You can't even believe
Someone can create such a work
This is not the only work by Michelangelo, right
It’s not just that
It seems that this is the period when he finished other incredible masterpieces
I took a few months to make it by the way.
This is a work about meditation
So it is placed in the great cathedral of the great city
The theme of this work is like saying
What will she do if she wakes up as a mother
A customer came to see me some time ago
That's a lady about 30 years old
Make personal decisions
She is very professional, so I asked her
Of course, her career development is also a little problematic
I've seen this kind of thing many, many times
This is a story and a hybrid
I talked to her about other elements in her life
There are only five things in life
Career is gone
What valuable things have you done outside of your career
How is your family
May be related to your native family
Related to your biological siblings and so on
Do you have a close relationship
What are your plans for your family
In addition to these five things
There are other things like exercise from time to time
Don’t eat too bad and stay away from crimes like drug abuse
That kind of lazy life
If you are missing any of these five things
Maybe you did any of them wrong
That's the trouble
You can escape some trouble
But can't hide everything
She said so
"I'm not sure if I want to have a baby"
I think "Gosh"
"Can you use your brain?"
I told her "you are too old-fashioned"
I said, "You should think about this when you are 16"
I was thinking "Really, can you only do this?"
This lady is very smart
So I was thinking, "Really, can you only do this?"
Of course there are bitterness and pain behind this
If you ask 30 people who are hesitant to have children
What are they hesitating
Twenty of them will say, "If you say too much, it will be tears."
You know how old this is
This is too old-fashioned so it doesn't constitute an idea
This is a cultural gene, it is rooted in your mind
This is not an idea
Of course you shouldn’t just look at the apparent value in this kind of thing
Say "Uh, I don't want to start a family"
If you still have a little review, you will also comment on the price
There is a very common idea
"There are too many people on Earth."
I really don't like this view
Who do you want to die
How to let them die
This is a serious question
Who is saying there are too many people
What is going on with these people
"We are wandering around and ruining the earth"
By the way, the Club of Rome had predicted
There will be more people on Earth by the year 2000
The point that led to a massive famine
These people are really wrong
I think it is the Club of Rome that sees us as
Virus or cancer on earth
Really? Is that how you treat humans?
How can you do this
Is it okay to treat humans as viruses and cancer?
What would you do to viruses and cancer
Invite them in and make them feel at home
Of course you will destroy them
You should examine your metaphor friends
Because it was you who came up with these metaphors
Or do they control your mind? It’s really not clear
So it is better to pay attention to them
Back to the topic
Mary is the Virgin and the role of "mother"
It doesn't matter whether she really exists
At least it can be said that she exists in a surreal sense
She exists as a Virgin
What kind of sacrifice did the Virgin made?
It's obvious
If you are a qualified mother
You will let your son be destroyed by the world
This is what a mother should do
This is bound to happen right
He will be born and suffer
Life is full of difficulties
He will get sick
Will experience failure and extinction
Eventually die
This is bound to happen
If you are sober you realize this
Then you say
Maybe this is the way to survive
Then you try to achieve these things
That's why you are worthy of this statue
But this is still a sacrifice made by the mother
Is it right to bring children into this bad world
Every woman asks herself this question
Some women's answers are no
They have their own reasons
Mary feels right spontaneously
Mary is the archetype of a woman willing to bring new life
This is the meaning of this picture
Not because she can't see
She knows what will happen
Mary is the archetype of a woman willing to bring new life
She fully understands the meaning of life
She is not naive
She's not the kind to be stupid because of being drunk
Woman accidentally pregnant in the back seat of a Chevrolet in 1957
It's not like this
She consciously
Know clearly what will happen in the future
And then allow these things to happen
This is another thing that can prove mother's courage
My mother is very good at this
She is very friendly
From the point of view of her personal interests, she is a bit too friendly
But the character with high affinity will be like this
Your affinity is so high that it hurts your own interests
This is the definition of affinity
She is a good person
Fortunately she is also
She is still alive and we are very close
It's a good thing that I can always make her laugh
But she is also an iron lady
I remember one time she happened to ran into
When I was young in the town where I grew up
Playing in an empty baseball field
I was about ten years old
She passed here
I am with a group of friends
I am going to fight with this bear kid who often plays with
Half of the team are girls
Fighting may have something to do with state and skill
Anyway, we are going to fight
My mother passed by here
She glanced here
I can tell from her behavior
She knows what is going to happen
She glanced at me and walked away
I thought to myself, "Wow mom did a great job."
I really don't want her to come over at that moment
Then said, "You kids are going to fight, right?"
Isn't it obvious
We are really ready to fight
If you come to stop
I lost before I started playing
So I really have to give my mom a thumbs up
She also said something before
I had conflicts with my father when I was a teenager
He and I have some conflicts
We two are evenly matched
Actually it should be 7 to 3
I am the one with more problems
I left home when I was 17
She said something very interesting when I left home
She said, "If you live well at home, you will never leave."
I thought to myself, "Mom said so well"
"For a person with high affinity
"You really have a backbone."
Really awesome
"Mother" will also say
"Go out and get frustrated."
"Because you are strong enough to handle it."
She doesn’t say, "You can just lie down in the bedroom."
"Because the world is unfair, it didn't treat you well"
"It made you suffer too much."
Instead, she would say "The outside world is indeed full of suffering"
"But you are stronger than you think."
"Mary’s son Christ dedicated himself completely to God
"In order to give him faith and trust in this world
"It will not be broken by betrayal torture and death."
"This is an example of a respectable person"
This is an interesting behavior
This is a mother who is willing to make sacrifices
Laid the foundation for her son
And this son is willing to make sacrifices
This result is very good
It's important to know this
"But for Christ
"When he sacrificed himself
"God his Heavenly Father also sacrificed his own son at the same time."
This is the strange thing about the Trinity model
That God sacrificed himself to himself
The same thing happened in Norse mythology, right
Is it Norse mythology? It should be Zeus
Germanic myth
Zeus sacrificed himself to himself
He hangs himself on the tree
And really got hurt
This is an interesting analogy
But I think part of the meaning is
Humans are trying to figure out
What is the ultimate sacrifice
Similar to the ultimate sacrifice of value
Passion
I said before that I was laying the groundwork
I want to mention things that will not be discussed in the near future
Maybe it won’t be mentioned in this series of lectures
Because i don't know where i can talk
The mother has a request for her to make the ultimate sacrifice
There is also a demand for his son to make the final sacrifice
There is also a request for his father to make the final sacrifice
And at the same time
This makes the ultimate sacrifice possible
And suppose this sacrifice brings recovery
This sacrifice brings recovery and salvation
This is a thought-provoking idea
It’s important
I don't know if it is correct
But I know its reverse is wrong
Generally speaking, the wrong thing is right
The opposite of this is wrong
Because if the Virgin does not make sacrifices
Your family will fall into a terrible Oedipus situation
Or something like this
This is very bad
If you want to explore this
I suggest you watch a documentary called "Kruper"
It is called the best documentary ever by some critics
This is really a good movie
This is the only one I have seen
A work that fully displays the Oedipus disaster
You can have a look
It's useless if the mother doesn't make sacrifices
If the father doesn’t make sacrifices
If the father is not willing to let his son go out
Be betrayed
Then there is no way to start
Because the child won't grow up
If my son is not willing to go out
So who will bear the responsibility?
If the sacrifice of the three parties did not happen
Everything is chaotic, disorderly and hellish
If all the sacrifices happen
Is this the opposite of chaos
you can say
Depends on the degree of these sacrifices
This is a continuous state
How thorough can they happen
We don't know
You might say
In the matter of "encourage your children to live in the truth"
How well you can do
This is a partial answer to this question
The answer is probably that you can’t do your best to do it
The result of this incident may be good
But you won't know
If you do this thing extremely well
How good the result will be
You won't know
People have hidden it
The interesting thing after having a baby is
There are two things you don't know
Actually there are more than two
There are three things you will know after you have children
The first is that you haven't grown up before
You won’t grow up until you have someone more important than yourself
You really don't
People think they will grow up without children
It’s just that they think so
Some people make other sacrifices
But in my opinion this is not the same
This is not an elegant metaphor
But you will find that not being the focus of other people’s attention is actually a relief
It's good because you can relax
Because of course your children are in the family and society
Will immediately become the focus of attention
You will let your child become the focus of attention
Unless you are a narcissist
Then you will find all kinds of shining points on others
Others also like babies
This is a good thing
We lived in Montreal when we raised our first child
The neighborhood we live in is not good by Montreal standards
Montreal is as good as Toronto
Even if it’s a slightly inferior neighborhood
It also brings a little dark side in the charming
There are also a few difficult people in the block
The whole neighborhood is not very rich
We will push her around
These gloomy and frustrated old people will come over
I became radiant when I saw her
They will come over and smile at her
You will see the positive elements of human nature emerge
If you don’t react like this to babies
Then you really have a serious problem
this is not good
But seeing these
These people wandering listlessly in the street
Suddenly their burdens and precautions were put down
Babies are a bit like public property, which is strange
Just like a pregnant woman
People usually treat pregnant women as public property
I mean positive
They will say "You are going to have a baby"
Then do some caring things for pregnant women
The reason I told you this is
People have a strong urge to understand
The birth of a new life is a miracle
The miracle is that this new life is full of potential
This is all the potential that new life represents
Every new life is born means
Possibility of the birth of great people
One thing I think about is
One thing you don’t know is
Before you have your own children
Children are nothing special to you
But your own child is special
At the moment of his birth, this child
Is someone who has a closer relationship with you
May be closer than your relationship with anyone
And you can keep this relationship perfect
Most of the relationships you have established
Are built with people who have problems in many ways
You are not perfect
But you now have this child
It hasn't been destroyed yet
You may maintain this relationship
This kid likes you very much
Generally it will last a long time
When they were two years old
They will be happy to see you when you go home
Like raising a puppy
The puppy is so happy when you go home
How many people will be happy when you go home
They might say "Hey again you"
But kids are not like this
The children are really happy when you go home
You can keep this happy
This is something that our society does not value
The rustic elements of the relationship between children and parents
As if we were covering our eyes voluntarily
This is really a disaster
Because it's really rare in life
There are things that compare with children to build healthy relationships
If you can maintain a good relationship with your children
They will be good company
It's worth the effort
The reason I tell you this is
People see baby
They will think this may be a potential savior of mankind
This is what they would think
They act like this, they think like this
Actually this is also true
I don’t know how real it is
But I think it might be because people are afraid to find the reason
At least in my opinion
"But for Christ
"When he sacrificed himself
"God his Heavenly Father also sacrificed his own son at the same time."
"This is in Christianity
"Sacrifice of son and self is the cause of archetype"
"There is nothing greater than this."
This is why it is a prototype
You can't go beyond it
"This is the definition of archetype"
"This is the core of the religion."
"In all possible sacrifices
"The sacrifice of self and children is the greatest"
"This is beyond doubt."
"Pain and suffering define the world"
"The same is true."
"Those who want to resolve suffering
"People who want the best possible future in architecture"
"Those who want to build heaven on earth
"So I will dedicate everything I have to God
"Dedicated to the life living in the truth"
This is the book I will publish in January
Part of it
Speaking of "Genesis", we have reached the fourth chapter
"One day that man had a room with his wife Eve
"Eve became pregnant and gave birth to Cain
"Just say
"The Lord gave me a man" (Genesis 4:1)
This happened after Adam and Eve were expelled from the Garden of Eden
what is interesting is
I really think the story of Cain and Abel
Is the deepest story I have ever read
Especially because you can tell this story in 15 seconds
I won’t tell a story in 15 seconds just because it’s hard for me
You may have noticed this too
But it’s so short you can read it right away
It is so concise and concise
I just can't
I can't believe it can be so concise and concise
First of all
Adam and Eve were not the first humans
Cain and Abel were the first humans
Adam and Eve were created by God
They were born in heaven
What kind of human is this
Humans are not like this
Human beings were not created by God and born in heaven
People are born of life
This is the first thing
This is after the "fall"
We are now in the long history
Not in the supernatural prototype
Although to some extent we are still in the supernatural prototype
But not to the degree of Adam and Eve
We have been expelled from the Garden of Eden
We already have self-awareness
We are already sober
We have learned to dress and work
We are sound humans
These are the first two humans
Cain and Abel are two human archetypes
It’s interesting that humans at the end of the Adam and Eve story
Into history
Then the prototype model of human behavior
Be revealed immediately
It's very unbelievable
This is not a very beautiful story
They are two rival brothers
It can be said that they are choking each other
Or at least one of them did
This is a story about the first two humans hurting each other
End with the death of the best one
This is the story of human beings who entered history
If this story can't make you have nightmares
Then you didn't understand it at all
In the stories of these hostile brothers
These stories are very common
Usually the brother is Cain
This is true in the Bible
Is true in many kinds of folktales
In almost all stories
Brother has an advantage
He is brother
In farming society
Usually the older brother inherits the land
Not brother
The reason is
Suppose you have eight sons
You have enough land to feed your family
You divide the land among eight sons
They also have eight sons
They divided their land among eight sons
Soon the land will be divided into tiny shares
Everyone will starve to death
this will not work
You give the whole land to the eldest son
This is the right way
Unfortunate for others
But at least they will work hard by themselves
It's really unfair, but fairness is really unattainable
You can say that the eldest son is in the steady state of the existing hierarchy
There are extra chips
He has more chips in the status quo
This makes him more like a symbol of the status quo
And it’s easier to get lost
It can be said like this
This theme often appears in the struggle between rival brothers
The story of Cain and Abel fits this pattern
Because Cain is the one who doesn't want to regress
He is stubborn
However, the second son Abel
He is usually
Can't be said to be revolutionary
May be more like a balance between revolution and tradition
The eldest son is more like a traditional authoritarian
At least in these metaphorical representations
"One day that man had a room with his wife Eve
"Eve became pregnant and gave birth to Cain
"They said that the Lord made me a man" (Genesis 4:1)
This is the first human Cain
I have said before that Mesopotamians think
Humans are imaginable by the goddess of chaos
Made by the blood of the most evil demon
The first human being was a murderer
Not just a murderer, he is a brother killer
You know the Old Testament
This is a very strict book
You think this is a bit too much
But you will feel it is real
This is something worth thinking about
Humans are amazing creatures
If you think of human beings as the plague of the earth
The idea itself is a disaster
Is a vicious and indecent
Genocide metaphor
But this does not mean that we are flawless
This book is the cornerstone of our culture
Describe the first human being as a brother killer
Is really a blow to us
"Cain's brother Abel was born again
"Abel is the shepherd and Cain is the farmer" (Genesis 4:2)
This is an old painting
Abel on the left
He put his sheep on the altar
Cain brought a handful of wheat ears
I am not very clear what this red line is
This is blood or rays
Almost like this
Generally speaking, something transcendent
Are communicating with this sacrifice
You will think this is very primitive
How primitive these people are to sacrifice to God
These people are not stupid
This is not original
Not original anyway
Its complexity is far beyond your imagination
As I said, the idea is
You can sacrifice something valuable
This sacrifice will have a transcendent effect
This is by no means a simple idea
In fact, this may be the best idea that humans have come up with
This answers the story of Adam and Eve
Questions raised
We have self-awareness
We found the future
We know the inevitability of death
Understand our vulnerability
We got shame
We have established the concept of good and evil
We were cast out of heaven
This is a serious problem
What should you do? The answer is sacrifice
This is a hypothesis
This is a very good assumption
This is exactly what we are doing
You make many sacrifices
Even if you can sit in this theater
Many people have made great sacrifices
To build such a theater
Many people made sacrifices
So that we can be free in such a theater
Engage in such a conversation
Everything is built on the basis of sacrifice
Sacrifice works best
Because we can't think of a better idea
What is the opposite of sacrifice
Murder and theft
Then let's stick to sacrifice, okay
And we shouldn’t judge it as primitive
This is by no means original
"Cain's brother Abel was born again
"Abel is a shepherd and Cain is a farmer" (Gen 4:2)
Some people interpret this as
The eternal struggle between the shepherd and the farmer
The war swept the western United States
The shepherd keeps his flock
Go where you want
Farmers and farmers built fences to block them
In the end, the farmer won
Back to the topic Abel is a shepherd
It's funny he became a shepherd
I think this is part of the critical issue
Because the shepherd we discussed earlier
If you observe Michelangelo’s "Statue of David"
"The Statue of David" is a shocking masterpiece
This David is not a small person
Obviously David was the one who killed Goliath
Goliath symbolizes the giant of the enemy of patriarchy
Almost like this
Shepherds in the Middle East take care of their sheep
Sheep is edible
Lamb is very fragile
There are many wild predators outside
Not the same as England in the 16th century
There were lions in the wild at that time
You are holding a slingshot or stick or what kind of weapon
Your job is to look after the sheep alone
Let them at least not be eaten by lions
You must be strong and independent
You have to have these qualities
You have to be strong and independent
You have to protect a lot of fragile things
You have to be able to do it independently
This is established in the shepherd metaphor
This is not a good metaphor for modern people
Because we would think
Shepherd is like "Little Boy"
Not to be a muscle monster that can kill lions
Shepherds are not like this. We think shepherds are easy
And the metaphor here is not like this
"Abel is the shepherd and Cain is the farmer" (Genesis 4:2)
"One day
"Cain took the produce from the field as an offering
"To the Lord" (Genesis 4:3)
So he participated in the sacrificial activities
"Abel also offered the firstborn of his flock and the fat of the sheep
"The Lord saw Abel and his offerings" (Genesis 4:4)
You don't understand why
I think there is some inherent ambiguity here
I’m not sure but I think it’s the context
"Abel also took the firstborn of his flock
"To offer the fat of sheep" (Genesis 4:4)
What does this mean
He brought high-quality sacrifices
You can't say that what Cain brought is bad
Because it is not said in the original text
Did not say that Cain brought some rotten vegetables and burned it
Didn't say so
But there is no word
Describe how high-quality Abel’s sacrifices are
but no matter
Jehovah has eyes on Abel and his offerings
So there is a hint that Abel prepared sacrifices
More attentive than Cain
But there are such hints
God likes you better than him
This is a meaningful point of view from a literary point of view
Because life is random
Like one of my children
He is always favored
He is lucky, whatever you want to describe
He seems to be this kind of person
And my other child
Just like Job, the unexplainable disaster followed one after another
This is a very strange phenomenon because
as far as I know
Differences in personality
Can't affect fate
This suffering child
She is really a great kid
She is happy, sunny, approachable and humorous
But she suffered too much
Who knows what god is going to do
Distributing fate fairly is certainly not one of his tasks
"The Lord saw Abel and his offerings" (Genesis 4:4)
"Just look down on Cain and his offerings
"Cain was very angry" (Genesis 4:5)
Angry is a serious word
These articles have been translated many times
It is difficult to grasp the full meaning of the word itself
"His face changed from anger" (Genesis 4:4)
So angry
This is to raise the complexion
Hanging face means heavy heart
He is depressed, that's for sure
He was furious, that's for sure
It's not impossible for him to hold resentment
"Get angry" is anger
So Cain is not happy
Because of his hard work was rejected by God
This is worth thinking about
How much humanity there is in this story
You in life
You may be a useless character
You complain about how bad your life is
For you and everyone around you
Obviously everything is your fault
You didn't make an effort
You didn't get up early
You are not looking for a job
You didn't commit yourself fully
You are full of cynical complaints and anger
You are not eager to help people around you
Don't try to save your life
You didn't take care of yourself
Then things became a mess
Otherwise what do you think
But that doesn’t mean that people in this situation will say
"Okay, I deserve it" and settle down
They won't
They will always complain and be angry
Let's not discuss this situation
Some people are working hard to face the suffering every day
But suffering still followed
There is no easy answer in this story
You can because your offering is inferior
And offend God
Or somehow you angered God
Then you are really unlucky
Then what will happen
In either case, almost inevitable is the following result
"Cain became very angry and his face changed" (Gen 4:4)
People like this always write to me
Many of my patients have this situation
Few people in their 20s are more in their 30s
Some in their 40s
Their life is not going well
Fell into despair
Not only in despair
They are still full of anger
God knows if you give them a chance to vent
What will they do with this anger
One thing I always think about Hitler is
Actually you have to convince Hitler
He is an organizational genius
Man will become Hitler's reason
People did not have the ambition to become Hitler
Not because they don’t have the motivation to destroy the race
They don't imitate Hitler
Because they don’t have this kind of organizational talent
They have this kind of motivation
If you randomly select 100 people
You communicate with them in depth
You will find 5% of people
If you give them a chance
They are willing to put their revenge plan into practice
In fact they do it
They make their lives miserable
Usually drag their family into the water
Sometimes they make everyone around them miserable
And the other 20% of them
It is normal for them to have such thoughts
You should be sympathetic to Cain
If you have no sympathy for Cain then you
Cain and Abel do not merely represent the archetypes of the two modes of being
It's not that you are Cain and you are Abel
But you are a combination of the two
Something like this
These are two potential modes of fate
You won’t fully show one kind of another
It's like the dividing line between good and evil in human hearts
This is exactly the same concept
Maybe you are more like Cain
Maybe you are more like Abel
But no matter how much you resemble Abel
You still have a little Cain in your heart
Maybe you’re just a little bit like Cain, maybe more than a little
If you observe your fantasy
I strongly recommend you to observe
You will find that if you allow yourself to be conscious of what you think
You will be surprised at the dark side of these fantasies
When you are arguing with someone
Especially arguing with the one you love
At this time you should observe carefully
A picture flashing from the depths of your mind
This is in part with Carl Jung’s
"Shadows" are connected
"Shadow" is Cain's manifestation
It's very reasonable to think like this
One of Jung's descriptions of "shadows"
Jung’s view is not a joke
He said that the roots of the "shadows" of mankind go straight to hell
Jung is serious
It's not a metaphor for him
The meaning of his sentence may be the same
Fundamentalist Christians in the Southern United States have a different understanding
But I think Jung’s meaning is more scary
And more real
"Cain became very angry and his face changed" (Gen 4:4)
In the middle of the picture is Abel burning his offering
He and this we temporarily call
"The original image of culture" establishes a certain relationship
Archetype of the Father
This is someone he respects
This posture implies respect
And Cain is here in the background
His face is shrouded in shadows
He is jealous of the status quo
He's just doing things
Maybe God really doesn't like him
We don't know
But he is really doing things perfunctory
He feels very upset
You can engrave this sentence on
Many people’s epitaphs on their tombstones
That is, "doing nothing but end in depression"
I think this picture is very interesting
I don't know what God is doing
He is helping to light the sacrificial flame
I think this is really interesting because
We assume you have the urge to make sacrifices
You think I have to change my life
So where does this impulse come from
It is out of nothing
Or you figured it out
You better not be so sure
Your ideas are all your own
Didn't you come up with your dream?
They just happened
God knows where they came from
"They come from the brain."
This answer is really brilliant
"They come from your unconscious"
This answer is not much better
But at least a little better
These amazing episodes at night
Happen in your hall of imagination
You don't even understand what they are
But they will appear every night
Dreams can also contain wisdom
If people can understand the main points of dreams and remember them
They will be very shocked
It's like watching
You reveal to yourself wisdom that you don't know
Where did this come from
You do not know
Why on earth can you dream of things you don't know
This is a problem
Maybe in a certain lecture
We will discuss this issue
Because about this question
There are still a few reasonable answers
There is such a theory that it is not yourself
Jung called it "self"
He thinks this is the sum of your existence across time and space
Almost like this
Every moment you exist
It’s the side of your "self" that crosses time and space.
He believes that "self" is part of the expression of conscience
No matter what "conscience" refers to this will be
Help you when you make difficult choices
The difficult choice may be what I need to sacrifice
How do I achieve self-discipline
What do i need to give up
How do you figure out these things
This painting is to express such an idea
If you have a good relationship with the Father
We discussed what it means
He will help you figure out how to light a sacrificial fire
So that you can maintain a good relationship with the Father for a long time
Is this an unreasonable proposal
What's the other proposal
What is certain is that Cain’s situation in the picture is not a good result
I don't know what Cain is doing
Maybe he thinks only he can do it
Or he just wants to take credit or something
He has neither gratitude nor humility
There is no gratitude or humility in his posture
The pious posture should be like Abel's
Should be grateful and humble
Gratitude should be
"Thank God for not making my life worse than the status quo"
You should be grateful
Because your life may be worse than the status quo
Your life can be very bad
Humility should be
"I don't know how I can do better
"But I am willing to listen to your suggestions."
"If I can figure out what to do, I will try hard."
This is humility and humility
How can i do better
Something like this
What kind of sacrifice do I need to make to make everything better
You should ask yourself this question
You can ask yourself every morning
What kind of sacrifice do I need to make to make everything better
You can decide what is the definition of "better"
Then this is not imposed on you
It’s you who figured out what constitutes "better" for you
Try to perfect this concept
You shouldn't just be better for yourself
It doesn't work is it
If you are only for yourself, you will only go downhill
Because you live with others
And this idea is stupid no matter what
What are you going to do
Really have nothing to say
This is the attitude of two-year-olds who behave misbehaving and sexually violent.
I'm not kidding
You can ask yourself
I have this whole day to plan
I need to give up something that hinders my progress
If I give up these things my life will be better
My family's life will be better
The cultural ecology behind me will get better
My being will become better
This will give you a plan for your day, right
This will prove the meaning of your miserable life
You need to do
This is the gist of the first story of Adam and Eve
What a miserable life do you have
What do you need to do
If your life is miserable
If you just endure the pain stupidly and complain
This is what Cain did
What if you choose not to
Making bad choices things can get worse
Then if you make sacrifices
See if you can please God to get the being back on track
This is what to do
Is there a better choice than this
Could there be a better option
This is why it is a prototype
Because there is nothing better than it, it is optimal
You can do it every day
You have to do it bit by bit
What are you
You can't send a cannon for humans
A socialist utopia
You can think of it this way. Cain might figure this out.
There are several things that are not good for him
Downstream of the wind
Not a good place to fan fire
The fact is that he is shrouded in smoke
And inhaling the haze
The fire didn't start
May indicate that he did something wrong
Or he said while wiping tears
"My God, what stupid world can give birth to such a haze"
This is the more likely result
"The Lord said to Cain
"'Why are you angry?
""Why have you changed your complexion?" (Genesis 4:6)
""Will you not be acceptable if you do well"" (Genesis 4:7)
This sentence is very interesting
I have seen many versions of translations in this seventh section
This is a very important sentence and its translation is really important
Let me tell you what I think the story is like
And what i figured out
I'm sure I didn't fully understand
God says "If you do well, won't you be acceptable?"
This is a hint right
It's like when you get frustrated
The first thing you will think is that you failed to do well
Does this mean what you are doing is not good
Does this mean your behavior is inappropriate
This is a reminder that God is suggesting
You will succeed if you behave properly
I once had a friend who said in a way
A person full of resentment
He used to have problems
Part of the problem is to blame
Part of the problem is destined. I think
He has become very destructive
I think it’s the kind of destructive life
Can be seen in his dreams
He lived with me for a while
I know him well
He has been my friend since I was 12
Until he committed suicide around 40
When he lived with me
I tried to cheer him up
This is why he came to live with me
Because he thinks maybe I can help him cheer up
He can only do some low-end jobs
He has some mechanical skills
Although he is not well educated
But very very smart
His IQ may be around 135
He is smart but unwilling
Because he didn't let himself be educated
Matches his intelligence
He can only do some work under his intelligence
He really has that intellectual arrogance and
Really smart people often believe that only smartness is the most important thing
If they are smart
And only being smart is the most important
Then the world will surrender to their feet
Then they will be betrayed brutally
Then they focus on their intelligence
At this time intelligence is more like a gift or genius
It's like an idol, a false idol
Is such a very dangerous idol
Because of the stupidity of the world
And they become cynical
But this is not helpful
Smart is a good thing but I want to tell you
If you don’t make good use of it, it will eat you back
Like all the talents given at will
You may have talent
But only by making good use of it will it become your friend
If you use it wrongly, it will become your enemy
Maybe God adjusts the scale of the universe in this way
In short, my friend is a very smart person
Although unfortunately not as smart as he imagined
He didn't make good use of his intelligence
Failed to show it to the world well
It also made him angry
Because he also knows
If he makes good use of his intelligence
His achievements will go beyond this
Maybe now he can achieve higher achievements
I suggest him when he is living with us
Because at that time he almost became a tramp
I suggest that he should find a job within his capacity
Jobs like working in garbage stations and shops
Because he is better at mechanical principles
I also suggest that he should give up that arrogance
I think this kind of job is not worthy of him
No job was not worthy of him in that situation
But more importantly
"Work is not worthy of people" actually doesn't make sense
You know because
Imagine you have a job at a grocery store
This is a fairly unskilled job
You can be a hapless grumbling while doing this job
It can also be an annoying person
You can go to work
Just lose your temper and complain and make mistakes
Guarantee any customer
When I pass by you, I have to stop for a day
You can steal from the busy or even guard yourself
Dissatisfied with the employer
Because they are higher than you in this dominance level
You can also talk bad and gossip behind your colleagues
You can accept this humble job that you think
Then transform it into a little hell
You can do it
You go to a place like this
I always think of such a prototype of a roadside snack bar
You have all been to this kind of shop
Of course there are also good restaurants
There is a very good video on YouTube
Tom Weitz read a poem in it
Written by Bukowski
I remember this poem is called "Nirvana"
This is a poem about a good store
Bukowski took the bus as a child
A small restaurant I visited by accident
It's a nice restaurant everywhere
You can listen to it is great
But this one I think of is completely different
You walk into the small restaurant
It's seven o'clock in the morning
You ordered bacon, eggs and some toast
You look around you think
The windows seem to have not been wiped since 1975
There is a thick layer of old oil stains on the surrounding walls
The floor is also slimy
It really takes years to do it
The waitress was glum there
The guy behind the counter also pulled his face
Because it happened to be on duty with the waitress
Then you go downstairs to the bathroom
And it took quite a while
You came back and ordered an egg
Ordered a toast and ordered a bacon
The rice came up, but the egg was fried
So it becomes brownish black but it's a bit raw on it
Still cold in the middle
You really need to spend some time to make this kind of egg
But ten years of resentment can let you easily control this technology
It will tell you how to make such an egg
Then it’s toast, here’s toast
You take white bread first
The kind of bread that no one wants to eat
And put it in the bread machine
Burn it
Wait a minute and let the toast pop out of the bread machine
Because it's burnt, we need to scrape off the black ash
You flick some crumbs to make them look less burnt
Then you wait for it to get cold and apply cold margarine
First of all it is not butter
But if you put on cold margarine
The cream will be spread like a honeycomb
Secondly, the margarine will condense into pieces and very dry
But very greasy
It's like a chic work of art
You put it next to the egg
Then bring potatoes
Here is how to make potatoes
First, we have to make leftover potatoes
And you have to keep putting new leftover potatoes for weeks
Mixed into old potatoes
Some potatoes can't be called potatoes
Some of them have already returned to the embrace of Mother Earth
You dump them on the grill
Then symbolically I don’t know what to say and burn it twice.
And throw it on the plate
You won't want to eat this stuff, no doubt
But this is the key
Then you have to take out the bacon
You have to make sure that you buy the worst bacon
So we can start
You throw them on the grill
For this, your grill must be overheated
So you fried bacon
There will be some place where there will be some place
It has a pleasant pig smell
Only the bacon that is very cheap and smashed will have
Or you can use that kind of breakfast sausage
If it wasn't for the brain water
No one would put this sausage within five meters of a person
Then you serve
The so-called orange juice was served together
The only thing that looks like an orange is the color
There is also coffee
How do you say this shop opened too early in the morning
This is the first condition
A cup of poor quality coffee started the day prematurely
It has been cold once or twice and reheated
Then you add whitening powder when you serve it
Now your breakfast is ready
Who likes to eat
This is breakfast, this is hell
And this is the hell you made by yourself
What would you do if you had such a restaurant
Because if you have such a restaurant
You will live a miserable life
You really worked hard on this matter
You go home and scold your wife and children
And yell at God
Because he actually created a world
Allow such a restaurant you run to exist
This is your bloody life
This is what God wants to warn of here
"If you do well, won't you be accepted?"
"If you don’t do well, sin at the door" (Genesis 4:7)
I actually checked a lot of translations for this sentence
Its next sentence is
"It will adore you but you will subdue it" (Genesis 4:7)
God wants to say like this
Things are not going well for you
But things will get better if you behave decently
But you did the opposite
Sin comes to your door
"Sin" means miss the target
But he used a metaphorical approach
This metaphor is like saying
Sin comes to your door like a cat in heat
You invited it in at the beginning
Then you let it do whatever it wants
It’s like you have entered a creative
He uses a sexual metaphor
You enter a creative exchange with it
And produce a result
No matter what you give birth to, that is your life
You know it well
After all you have self-awareness
You know what you are doing
You conspired with it
Create a situation where you put yourself in it
Jung once described it
Similar to Oedipus complex
Of course his views are not politically correct
Of course everything he wrote is not politically correct
That's why it can be called a thinker
He said that an evil alliance exists in
Between children who are extremely dependent on others and their mothers
He said actually
Freud thought it was about motherhood
I'm not belittling Freud
Freud geniusly sketched the Oedipus complex
But Jung accepted these ideas and extended them
He said that an evil alliance exists in
In a child who is extremely dependent on others
With an Oedipus complex
Between mothers who are too dependent on others
In this alliance, mothers always give
So for example, when a child wants to do something
When things require a little courage and hard work
And the mother would say "Do you think you can do it?"
Then the child will say "Yes" or "No"
Then his mother will coax him to bed and take care of everything
But the fact is that the child also made a decision
You would think it's cruel to children
But don’t think children are stupid just because they are young
If you don’t know how children understand
You don’t know how to manipulate the child
They are unexpectedly good at this
He will keep studying you trying to figure out
What is your intention
2. How can they achieve their goals as they wish
They can play manipulation games without a doubt
Especially when they practice hard
Kind of like this
Maybe the mother is a little timid and overprotective
And the child may manipulate a little
I'm not willing to take a brave step to integrate into the world
On the contrary, they are willing to degenerate into a dependent state
Over time, a terrible dynamic will be established
Like a vicious circle
Or like a positive feedback loop
It keeps expanding and expanding
Sometimes in some families you can see
Have a very attached child
Share the same mother with a very independent child
Mother is very complicated
The mother is different for child A and child B
Even if they are the same person
Have a clear description of this literary work
You should know what I mean
God's will is
Not only pay attention to whether you behave properly
Because you did misbehaving
It’s because of your misbehavior
You really spent time researching how to misbehave
This seems to be your creative endeavor
If you want to understand the real vicious person
You can start with the Columbine campus killer
They leave many interesting diaries
I recommend everyone to read
You can read more about serial killers
These people really went out and did some very dark things
I read a lot of this stuff
And know it very well
If you really want to make yourself hateful
Then think about your own disaster for ten years
Be alone and let your fantasy take shape to encourage them
Let them blossom and bear fruit, in other words let them control you
This is the correct idea to understand this diary
It will bring you to such a situation
There are more people like this than you think
And you are more like this kind of person than you think
So Cain is obviously very unhappy with the whole answer
If your people generate a disaster
This is the last thing you want to hear
And in your heart, God created the world
And this world allows this kind of thing to happen
In the end it said it was your own fault
And said you should cheer up
And you should not complain about the nature of being
This is the answer he got
What will happen next
We can almost conclude
If Cain was resentful before
Then he is even more angry now
Of course this is exactly what the story intends to reveal
"Cain speaks with his brother Abel
"The two are in the field
"Cain got up and beat his brother Abel
"Kill him" (Genesis 4:8)
I am going to read something else to everyone
Pave the way for the back
Also this part comes from the same chapter of my book
The chapter is titled "Do meaningful things, not expedients"
"According to the story
"'Jesus was led into the wilderness by the Holy Spirit" (Matthew 4:1)
"Be "tempted by the devil" before being nailed to the cross (Matthew 4:1)"
"This is an abstract retelling of Cain's story."
"As we see Cain is very unhappy."
"He works hard or he thinks so
"But God is not satisfied"
"At the same time Abel is dancing among the daisies"
"His harvest, women also like him."
"What's worse is that he is a very good person."
"Everyone understands this."
"He deserves his luck."
"This adds another reason to hate him."
I used to make jokes when I taught at Harvard
My wife will invite young graduate students to be guests at home from time to time
Afterwards we often make jokes
Because most of them are outstanding children
They are extremely smart or possess sports expertise
Or have theatrical or musical talent
Or have done a remarkable charity act
Because I basically have to be admitted to Harvard
You must be the top person in your school
Then you need to have at least
Two other outstanding advantages
The most annoying thing about most of these kids is
This is a joke, you really like and respect them
My joke is
You think they must have at least some desirable qualities
To be a nasty bastard
Except for all other advantages in them
They also need to behave nicely
So you think
"Such good things should happen to them"
Gosh
It's like Abel's situation
The funny thing is that this is an ideal
This is the ideal
It can be said that this is an ideal person
This is the person you want to be
What this person does in this world
Is what you want to do
This person is favored by fate
This person made the right sacrifice
This is who you want to be
So Cain killed him
This is also a psychological story
When people express cynical views about successful people in the world
You can find this psychology
They are always speculating about the reasons for their success
"They must do whatever it takes."
"They must be scheming."
"They must be arrogant and rude"
"They must be mentally perverted."
Of course these all exist
But self-deception is a terrible trick
Think this person in the world
The person who represents your ideal
It's all created by despicable reasons
Because you will train yourself accordingly
If the ideal life you should pursue exists, it can only be
Motivated by despicable reasons
Then, not only Abel, your brother died
Just like your brother in reality in the field
At the same time you have destroyed your ideals
What are you going after?
How will you live
There is no doubt that it is full of misery and pain
Full of complaints and misery
You will live like this
I rarely see it especially in public
People honestly admit that except for sports stars
This place seems to happen
But people in any public communication
It is rare to express admiration and gratitude
Various newspapers and TV shows on YouTube and Twitter
Almost always slander and criticism
And often for those
Those single-minded
People who benefit others
This is one reason why this story has a profound meaning
"He is a nice guy everyone knows"
"His luck deserves it"
"There is more reason to hate him." No doubt
"Cain is anxious about his misfortune
"Like a vulture hatching an egg"
"He entered the desert of his own mind."
"He was trapped by his own misfortune and betrayal."
"He nourishes his resentment"
"He is addicted to more and more detailed revenge fantasy"
"His arrogance reached the level of Lucifer."
"'I have been abused and oppressed,' he thinks."
""This is a stupid damn earth" should go to hell"
"In this case he met Satan in the wilderness
"And captured by Satan's temptation"
"He did his best
"To use the timeless words of John Milton
"'Uproot humans
"『Make the earth and hell mixed together
""Let everyone hate the great Creator""
"He became evil in order to obtain good forbidden him to get"
"When he did this, he was voluntarily sober and malicious."
""Whoever has ears to hear should listen" (Matthew 11:15)"
The picture shows the first two humans
A loser full of grudges and complaints
Picked up the axe and slashed at the admirable winner
"The Lord said to Cain, "Where is your brother Abel?"
"He said, "I don't know
"Am I the guardian of my brother" (Genesis 4:9)
"The Lord said, "What have you done?"
"'Your brother's blood has a voice
""Well to me from the ground" (Genesis 4:10)
"『I opened my mouth
"'Receive your brother's blood from you
""Now you will be cursed from this land"" (Genesis 4:11)
If you want to understand this sentence then I suggest
You can read "Crime and Punishment" by Dostoevsky
This is a great novel
I think it may be the greatest novel to date
I haven't read all the novels but according to my experience
This is the greatest novel worthy of its name
It tells the psychological changes when you commit a big crime
Amazing
Psychologists like Dostoyevsky are unparalleled in the world
"『You farm
"'The land no longer works for you
"'You will drift away on the ground'" (Gen 4:12)
"Cain said to Jehovah
"'My punishment is too heavy
""More than I can be"" (Genesis 4:13)
One of the interesting things is
I think the punishment God imposed on Cain
It's like the inevitable consequence of Cain's actions
It means he killed his brother
Death cannot be resurrected
You will never forgive yourself for this
Not to mention he is an ideal he is your ideal
Because you not only killed your brother
Of course you also torture your parents and other relatives
You wiped out a righteous person in your community
And because of the most vicious motive
Then your good day is over
Want me to say this is what you can do on earth
The closest thing to hell
"Cain said to the Lord
"'My punishment is too heavy
""More than I can be"" (Genesis 4:13)
"'You are chasing me out of this place now
""So that I can't see you"" (Genesis 4:14)
It is true that after making this kind of mistake
You can't turn back the prodigal son and convert to God
Because you have tried your best
To offend God, if he exists
The possibility that you can repair this relationship
This relationship in a severed state
It was impossible to fix from the beginning
Because you did such a bad thing before
The possibility of this repair approaches zero
""Whoever meets me will kill me" (Genesis 4:14)
"The Lord said to him
"'Whoever kills Cain will be punished seven times'
"The Lord gave Cain a mark
"Lest people meet him and kill him" (Genesis 4:15)
This is an interesting thing
I used to think for a long time
You might not figure it out
Why should God shelter Cain
And on the premise that he committed such atrocity
I think this is related to the emergence of an idea
That is to say, it is necessary to prevent "retaliation" style retaliatory killings
Roughly what it means
This is implied in later chapters
It's like okay i killed your brother
Then you killed my two brothers
Then I killed your family
Then you killed people in my entire town
Then I killed you all over the country
Then we destroyed the world together
This should not be a clever way to solve the original problem
Despite the initial problem
It may be about murder that is not easy to solve
But i think so
The last part of this story
This painting is the work of William Black
Adam and Eve found their dead son
I think Cain also started to realize
What he did and what he was
This is another way to self-awareness
Adam and Eve are in the process of forming self-awareness
Very painful
They begin to recognize their own fragile nudity
And maybe they have the ability to do evil
But Cain began to realize that he was
Willing to walk with evil
And think this is a vital ability for humans
We modern people
We don’t take this seriously
In academic circles and intellectual circles
The idea of ​​evil has been
Everyone will ask "Where did you come from?"
"When was the Middle Ages?"
If a topic as a starting point of knowledge
This whole idea of ​​"evil" will die before you get away.
This is something I have never understood
I can't understand how you did it
There is only a superficial understanding of the history of the 20th century
No need to have a deep understanding of 20th century history
After that, but failed to draw the following conclusions
"Good may not exist but evil"
The existence of evil is ironclad
Denying its existence can only mean pretending to be invisible
This is a very useful discovery for me
I can also infer that if evil does exist
Then according to the inference, its opposite should also exist
The opposite of evil
Take the evil in the concentration camp as an example
Our understanding of the above will be more clear
This happened in Auschwitz
They drove people off the train at the station
Those who are still alive
Not the people crowded together outside the car
They have been frozen to death due to the cold
But those who are squeezed in the middle to be warmer
Maybe some old people will die from suffocation
But at least some people were still alive when they arrived in Auschwitz
They drove these poor people out
One of the tricks soldiers often play against them is
Let the new prisoners carry
Sacks containing approximately 45 kg of wet salt
Move from one end of the camp
These camps are huge
Like a city
It's not like a gym, it's like a city
Thousands of people are there
They let these people carry wet salt bags
From one end of the camp to the other and back
This is ironic of a concept
That is "work gives you freedom"
It’s like saying "Think beautiful"
"You are exhausted and exhausted here."
In a sense it wants to explain the opposite of sacrifice
We let you do your job
But it can only speed up your death
Maybe we can embellish it
Because it will not only speed up your death
It will also proceed in a painful way
It also raises a possibility
That is to say, other people are suffering from the same disease, it is better to die
There is no doubt that this is an art
If you understand this kind of thing
Don’t think this is evil yet
Then you will understand what this means to you
"So Cain left the presence of the Lord
"Go and live in the land of Nod, east of Eden" (Genesis 4:16)
"Cain had sex with his wife
"His wife became pregnant" (Genesis 4:17)
There is a criticism
A common criticism of "Bible" stories
That is, "If Cain and Abel are
"The only two children of Adam and Eve
"So where did the others come from"
"Does this story seem a bit brainless"
No, this question will make the reader seem brainless
I mean are you serious
Is this the best criticism you can think of
You might say "Oh, you didn't catch the point"
And the correct answer to this criticism is
"You didn't catch the point."
"Cain had sex with his wife and his wife became pregnant
"Born Enoch
"Cain built a city" (Genesis 4:17)
It was Cain who built the city and started civilization
This is also unacceptable
This is the first brother killer
Built a city named after his son Enoch
"Enoch beg Enoch" (Genesis 4:18), etc.
I will skip generations here
"Lamech married two wives
"One named Yada
"One named Zela" (Genesis 4:19)
Here is an attempt to outline the genealogy
And describe in these tribal communities
To some degree
"Ada Sheng Ya 8
"Yaba is living in a tent
"The Patriarch of People Who Keep Livestock" (Genesis 4:20)
"Jabal’s brother’s name is Jubal
"He is everything
"The ancestor of those who play the piano and flute" (Gen 4:21)
"Zela gave birth to Tubal Cain again
"He made all kinds of bronze and iron weapons" (Genesis 4:22)
Tubal Cain is traditionally speaking
Is the first person to make weapons of war
"Lamech" returns to the descendants of Lamech Cain
"Lamech said to his two wives
"Ada Zela listen to my voice
"Lamech’s wife listens to my words
"The mature man hurt me and I killed him
"The young man hurt me and I killed him" (Genesis 4:23)
"If Cain was killed seven times
"Kill Lamech will be punished seventy-seven times" (Genesis 4:24)
A tendency I see here
Is Cain’s ability to murder
With the development of society
This ability has also developed into murder intent
This goes beyond just killing brothers
In the beginning it was "You hurt me, I will retaliate with hurt"
And then "You hurt me
"I'm going to kill you and six other people."
Then developed to
"Not 7 people killed but 70 people"
So there is a view
Once the first seed of murder is planted
It will grow exponentially
This is a warning
This is why I think Tubal Cain
This descendant of Cain
Was the first to make weapons of war
The story about Cain and Abel is almost told
As far as I am concerned, this story is not trivial
I think this story is always worth thinking about
Because there are too many angles to interpret it
I think the point revealed by these angles is
The potential of this story
Once understood
Not only will you recognize your failure
Or to recognize your rejection by being
And recognize your tendency to murder the best
And the tendency to murder the best in your own heart
Just for revenge
Because that means
We know that as Adam and Eve committed the original sin
The knowledge of good and evil has also come to the world
Recognizing that tendency means that now
Humans not only have to deal with
Tragedy and suffering
Even sacrificing properly is in vain
And bring real malice into the world
So there is a "degenerate" into history
Then I discovered that sacrifice is a good medicine for "depravity"
Then look back and find
Malicious appearance
Became a sacrificed enemy
That’s the story of Cain and Abel
This lecture comes to an end, thank you everyone